Hyeonmin Lee

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at Seoul National University (SNU), advised by Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Network Convergence and Security Lab).

My research interests focus on network security and its measurement: Are we using the network correctly and securely? How can we make the network (more) secure?

PERSONAL INFORMATION

EMAIL: hmlee@mmlab.snu.ac.kr

ADDRESS: Network Convergence and Security Lab., 5F, Building 301, 1,

Gwankak-ro, Gwanak-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

HOMEPAGE: https://hyeonmin-lee.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

NETWORK SECURITY — (especially) DNS security, Mail security SECURITY MEASUREMENT

EDUCATION

MAR 2016 - FEB 2022

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

- Dissertation: "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- Advisor: Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon

MAR 2011 - FEB 2016 **B.S.**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

FALL 2014

Visiting Student, Information Technology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

PUBLICATIONS

Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP (to appear)

Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2022

A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2020

Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Song

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information (JCCI), Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things

Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon Elsevier Computer Networks (SCI-E)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Apr 2020 - Present	Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle • Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP) • Role: Researcher / Programmer
MAR 2021 - NOV 2021	Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis • Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC)
	Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / Researcher / Programmer
APR 2016 - DEC 2020	Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity • Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP) • Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer
FEB 2020 - Nov 2020	Research on GPU Acceleration for Fully Homomorphic Encryption • Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC) • Role: Programmer
SEP 2019	Developing High-performance Programming Environments and Computing
- Apr 2020	SystemsSupported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)Role: Programmer
Aug 2019 - Nov 2019	Research on Distributed Web Structure and Counterplan • Supported by Korea Internet and Security Agency (KISA) • Role: Researcher
SEP 2018	Research on Trust and Security Scheme for Interconnection of Heteroge-
- Nov 2018	neous NetworksSupported by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)Role: Researcher
AUG 2016 - FEB 2019	Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model • Supported by Giga KOREA Foundation • Role: System Designer / Programmer
MAR 2016	Content Delivery Framework Using Spatial and Temporal Dynamics in Mo-
- MAY 2016	bile NetworksSupported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)Role: Programmer
JUL 2015	Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Low-
- DEC 2015	power SoCSupported by Samsung ElectronicsRole: Programmer

PATENTS

Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof

- Registration No. 1022656110000
- Republic of Korea, Jun. 10, 2021

Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System

- Registration No. 1020231150000
- Republic of Korea, Sep. 11, 2019

EXPERIENCES

MAY 2019

Visiting Researcher

- AUG 2019

The Center for Cybersecurity, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, USA

• Topic: Measuring and analyzing the ecosystem of DANE protocol in Email

SPRING 2016

Teaching Assistant

Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

• Class: Engineering Frontiers and Leadership 2

MISCELLANEOUS

MAR 2019 - FEB 2022

Expert Research Personnel (military service)

Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

The expert research personnel system is a form of alternative military service in Republic of Korea, where the military service is fulfilled by conducting research at a domestic university or company for three years. I had not been involved in any military research project throughout the service.